Hello everyone and welcome
to another lesson at English pod.
My name is Marco and I am
Katherine and today we're talking about
shopping online. So this is
an elementary level lesson.
That's right. We are going to shop for
things online. So before we get started
with this dialogue,
let's take a look at one
word we have for you
on vocabulary preview.
vocabulary preview.
Okay, the word we're
looking at today is eBay. eBay.
Okay, so this is a proper noun.
It's a actual website eBay.com.
That's right, it's
kind of like a store on
the internet for people
who want to buy used things.
Okay, so maybe if
you have a TV that
you don't want anymore, you go on eBay,
you put pictures of it online and you offer
it and anyone can
buy it. That's right.
So you can be a buyer. That
means you buy things or a seller.
So you sell things.
So this is interesting. Usually
you find that used things
on eBay, but you can
also find new things.
You can. It's kind of like
the Chinese website Taobao.
I've actually even seen
people selling cars on eBay.
Cars. Yeah. I can't imagine
buying a car on the internet. Really. No,
they have even very luxurious cars on eBay.
So we'll talk about more
about online shopping
a little bit later on.
But now why don't
we listen to our
dialogue for the first time
and then we'll come
back in just a little bit.
What are you doing? I'm just looking for
a nice pillow on eBay. You're shopping for
a pillow online.
That's absurd. Why?
I don't have to leave the
house or browse a dozen
stores to find what
I'm looking for.
This way, I just search for
it online quick and easy.
Let's see. But how do you pay for it? How
do you know you aren't going to be ripped
off by the seller? Well,
the website handles a
point system where if the seller does
something wrong, people comment negatively.
And then you know that he
or she may not be trustworthy.
Wow, that sounds pretty safe. So how
do you pay? Do you need a credit card?
You can use a credit
card or your debit card.
They also let you use the PayPal
system, which is really safe and fast.
I have never had any problems with
someone hacking my information or anything.
Do you think I can find a
sweater for my dog online?
You can find
anything. Are you sure
you want to start shopping online though?
Once you step into this world, there is no
route heading back. Let's
do it. All right, we're back. So
now we have four key words
for you on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. The first
word you might have already
heard us use already.
We're talking about
going on the internet
to do something. So we
say to go online. Okay.
So by saying that you
are going online, you say
that you are using the internet.
That's right. So
you can shop for
something online. Online
means the internet, right?
On the internet. So we don't say in the
internet. We say we're on the internet.
For example, he's been on the internet all
day long. I want to use the computer. Okay.
So I can say he's been online all day long.
That's right. Okay. So that is online.
And when we go online
and we are looking through
different websites or
maybe we are looking
at items on eBay, we
are browsing. Okay.
The verb here is to
browse. Now to browse is
to look at, but not carefully. Just to look
at with maybe the idea to shop or to buy
later. Okay. So you can
use browse for online
things, but you can
also use it for physical
things like you are in a
shop. You are browsing.
That's right. So I
can go to a clothing
store and I can browse. For example, if the
woman at the clothing store says, would you
like to buy something? I
say, no, I'm just browsing.
I'm just looking.
Okay. Very good.
And then when they were talking about eBay
and how it works, the person mentioned that
they have a point
system. All right.
A point system. Now, this is something you
hear about a lot on websites these days.
For example, many
websites have different users.
And so how do I know which
users or which, in this case,
sellers are the best? Well,
we have a point system.
More points means better, fewer points
means worse. Right. You might also call
this a star system. So
basically, a point system
is a way to show who is a very good community
member and who is not. That's right.
And that takes us to our
next word. So if a person has
a lot of points in their point system,
that means they are trustworthy. Okay.
Trustworthy is an
adjective. He is trustworthy.
They are trustworthy. This
means that I can trust them.
They are reliable. That's right. So I don't
think they will lie to me. I don't think
they will cheat me. Okay. So
a person can be trustworthy.
A company can be trustworthy.
Right. Or you could say, he never pays me
back. He's not very trustworthy when I lend
him money. Okay. Very
good. So four key words there.
Why don't we
listen to them again
in our dialogue and we'll be back shortly.
What are you doing? I'm just looking for
a nice pillow on eBay. You're shopping
for a pillow online? That's absurd. Why?
I don't have to leave the
house or browse a dozen
stores to find what I'm
looking for. This way,
I just search for it online quick and easy.
I see. But how do you pay for it? How do
you know you aren't going to be ripped off
by the seller? Well, the website handles
a point system where if the seller does
something wrong, people comment negatively.
And then you know that he
or she may not be trustworthy.
Wow. That sounds pretty safe.
So how do you pay? Do
you need a credit card?
You can use a credit
card or your debit card.
They also let you use
the PayPal system, which is
really safe and fast.
I have never had any
problems with someone hacking
my information or anything.
Do you think I can find a sweater for
my dog online? You can find anything.
Are you sure you want
to start shopping online
though? Once you step
into this world, there
is no turning back.
Let's do it. All right.
We're back. So now we have three
key phrases that we saw in our dialogue.
And let's take a look at
those now and fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Well, the first phrase we
have here is related to that last word we
had, trustworthy. Someone is not trustworthy
if they will rip you off. Okay. Okay.
So it's a phrasal verb to
rip you off or to rip off,
to rip someone
off. That's right.
So they ripped him
off. He ripped her off.
This means to steal money from
someone or to cheat someone.
Right. So maybe if a
pair of shoes usually
at a store costs $50.
And then your friend
sells them to you for $200,
your friend ripped you off.
That's right. He ripped you off.
That's not a good friend.
He's not very trustworthy.
All right. So now
when they were talking
about how safe it is to
make purchases online,
the person explained
that it's pretty safe and
that no one has ever
hacked his information.
Okay. So this is an
important verb that has
to do with the internet.
To hack information
is to steal information
on the internet.
So someone who hacks,
who steals this information
is called a hacker. Okay.
And this is something
that's very bad. We
want to go to secure
and safe websites because we don't want
people to hack our personal information.
That's right. Okay.
So the verb is to hack.
And finally in the end,
when they were going
to look for a sweater
for a dog, the person
said, you know what?
This is great. Are you sure
you want to start to shop online?
Once you do this, there is no turning back.
Oh, I love this phrase.
There's no turning back.
So this is, well, you think
about someone who's leaving.
You say, there's
no turning back.
You can't go back. You can't
return to where you were.
This is something
we say as a warning.
So listen, this is
your final decision.
If you say yes, you
cannot change your mind.
You cannot say no later.
So you can't turn back later.
That's right. So there's no turning
back now. Okay. No turning back.
Very good. Interesting phrases,
keywords and everything.
So we should listen
to this dialogue
one last time. And we'll be back
to talk with you a little bit more.
What are you doing? I'm just looking for
a nice pillow on eBay. You're shopping for
a pillow online.
That's absurd. Why?
I don't have to leave the
house or browse a dozen
stores to find what
I'm looking for.
This way, I just search for
it online quick and easy.
Let's see. But how do you pay for it? How
do you know you aren't going to be ripped
off by the seller? Well,
the website handles a
point system where if the seller does
something wrong, people comment negatively.
And then you know that he
or she may not be trustworthy.
Wow. That sounds pretty safe. So how
do you pay? Do you need a credit card?
You can use a credit
card or your debit card.
They also let you use
the PayPal system, which is
really safe and fast. I have
never had any problems
with someone hacking
my information or anything.
Do you think I can find a
sweater for my dog online?
You can find anything.
Are you sure you want
to start shopping online
though? Once you step
into this world, there
is no turning back.
Let's do it.
All right. So now talking
about online shopping.
Have you ever bought
anything online?
Use your credit card online? I have.
I've used my credit card on amazon.
com to purchase
books on the internet.
But I know that you
are much more of a
fan of online shopping.
You use the Chinese website
how about all the
time? Yeah. Well, actually,
I wrote this dialogue
and it's kind of based on
something real because
sometimes going to the
stores, it can be great
and you can see things and
physically touch them. But
I'm a little bit more practical.
I know exactly what I
want or maybe I saw it.
So I don't want to
have to go to the stores
and deal with, you know,
haggling or negotiating
or sometimes it's
even more expensive.
So I just, you know, from
the comfort of my own home,
just put in my debit
card number and buy
things online and I get
it delivered overnight.
Well, and you never
go shopping now.
We'll shopping. You have
to go to the clothing store for
clothes, the video games
store for video games.
And on the internet,
it's all in one place.
You're at home.
You're in your pajamas.
You use your credit card. And
the cool thing is that you can
even sometimes you
want to buy small things.
Like in this case, maybe a
pillow or you want to buy
like recently, I bought some
candles, some decorative candles.
So I don't know, do you really
want to go out downtown?
Look for the candle shop where you
can get them. You can just do it online.
Do it online. Let us know.
Do you shop on the internet?
If you do, what kind
of services do you use?
What stores do you
go to? Let us know.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you there.
All right. Bye, everyone. Bye.